<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>pte-preparation.com RSS feed</title>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com.com</link>
<description>PTE preparation study material with free PTE tips and strategies</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>Copyright (C) 2017 pte-preparation.com</copyright>

<item>
<title>Improve Speaking, Writing, Listening, Reading with tons of FUN! part 2</title>
<description>Children, from a young age are familiarized with these language codes called alphabets and the sounds associated with them. As they progress, they learn to interpret alphabets in context of words with their meaning and sentences and...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=37</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 15:40:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Improve Speaking, Writing, Listening, Reading with tons of FUN! part 1</title>
<description>It is agreed by linguists and other academicians that the best way to learn and master any language is to do it the same way an individual learns his/her first language. Children are not smart or have the experience, knowledge or intellectual abilities of an adult. They wear diapers, vomit, and make a mess while...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=36</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 17:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Academic Reading Tips for PTE</title>
<description>An alternative strategy is to read the question with the objective of understanding the topics and sub topics and the context in which these topics will be presented in the text. When you are done reading the question recall what information you have on the topics/sub topics. If you can predict...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=35</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tips to Improve Reading Skills for PTE Success</title>
<description>Listening and reading are the two bedrocks on which one builds and further develops one's English language skills. Hence, when you work on listening and reading skills, you will also improve...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=34</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 6 May 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>How to Select the Best Online PTE Preparation Course</title>
<description>The internet is flooded with various websites providing PTE preparation courses and practice tests. Naturally, it leaves test takers wondering about where to get the best PTE preparation and spend...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=33</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>IELTS Vs PTE - In-depth Guide</title>
<description>At first, test takers had just two options: IELTS or TOEFL. Then in 2009 Pearson launched Pearson Test of English (PTE). Ever since PTE acceptance level has grown and its fast becoming the test of choice for institutions, governments...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=32</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Write From Dictation - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>Write from dictation item type is remarkably similar to repeat sentence item type. Like in repeat sentence item type, here too...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=31</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Highlight Incorrrect Words - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>Preparation time of 10 seconds is just sufficient time for you to read the transcription given and prepare yourself to listen to the audio recording. Through your first...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=30</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Select Missing Word - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>What is expected is that you predict and choose from a set of options, the last few words of the speaker. So, listen as if you are on a...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=29</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Listening MCQ, Choose Single Answer - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>You can interpret these sub skills as the task that the question may require you to perform and the purpose with which you are to listen to the recording...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=28</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Highlight Correct Summary - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>Highlight correct summary item type is similar to Listening, multiple-choice, choose single/multiple answers item types. In fact, it is easier then these other PTE item types. Unlike the multiple choice item types...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=27</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Listening, Fill in the Blanks - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>Listening, fill in the blanks is one of the easiest item types in the PTE test. As you will see further down in the blog this item type is basically like a spelling test...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=26</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Choose Multiple Answers - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>All it takes is a little practice. In this blog, we will suggest strategies and tips for "Before Listening", "During Listening" and "While Answering" to help you go through this item type...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=25</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Summarize Spoken Text - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>To develop a winning listening strategy, we experimented with two common strategies that could be applied to listening. One group applied the most common strategy amongst test takers, to take notes while listening in order to formulate a summary later. The other group took...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=24</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Summarize Spoken Text - Understand the Game</title>
<description>Summarize spoken text is one of the few question types that test takers struggle with. However, you will be surprised to know that most students with average English skills manage to...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=23</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Summarize Spoken Text - Understand the Game</title>
<description>Summarize spoken text is one of the few question types that test takers struggle with. However, you will be surprised to know that most students with average English skills manage to...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=23</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Reading and Writing, Fill in the Blanks - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>Re-read the text to see if the word choices fit in coherently with the message of the text and make sense. If you have doubts about a blank; apply the...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=22</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Fill in the Blanks - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>When judging the appropriateness of a word choice for a blank always check if it meets the grammatical and common sense criteria...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=21</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Re-order Paragraph - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>The task to put text boxes together in the correct order in re-order paragraph question is similar to putting a jigsaw puzzle together. The skills required...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=20</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>MCQ, Choose Multiple Answers - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>However, there are few question types, like where the test taker is supposed to infer the gist of the reading text, which most PTE test takers struggle with...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=19</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>MCQ, Choose Single Answer - Understand the Game</title>
<description>However, there are few question types, like where the test taker is supposed to infer the gist of the reading text, which most PTE test takers struggle with. Then there is the element of time, where students...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=18</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>How to plan and write your essay</title>
<description>What test takers do not know or are confused about is, how to compose and present their arguments in a logical manner in these parts in an academic essay...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=17</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Write Essay - Understand the Essay Question</title>
<description>Understanding the essay question is the first and most important step towards writing a good essay. Through this exercise, you learn the essay question's</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=16</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Write Essay - Understand the Game</title>
<description>At the base of these problems is basically the fear of essay question type. In this section we will describe strategies and tips to overcome this fear and tackle problems with clarity...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=15</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Summarize Written Text - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>You know the reading paragraph that you will come across for summarize written text in the PTE test will always be academic by character. What you may not know is that academic texts are different...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=14</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Summarize Written Text - Understand the Game</title>
<description>However, to understand and implement these strategies you must first, understand the rules of the game...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=13</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Answer short question - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>Answer short question is the simplest and easiest question types in the PTE test. The fact that there are 10 questions in this item type, is a blessing for PTE test takers as...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=12</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Re-tell lecture - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>In this blog, you will find tips and strategies that will make the re-tell lecture question type seem like a walk in the park and help you score well, consistently...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=11</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Re-tell Lecture - Understand the Game</title>
<description>Once you understand the challenges that you will face and the skills that you have to display in this question type; you will be prepared to...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=10</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Vocabulary and phrases for Describe Image</title>
<description>In this blog, you will find words and phrases to help you express what you see in an image. If you are able...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=9</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Describe Image - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>In this blog, you will find strategies and tips that will make describe image question type seem like a walk in the park...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=8</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Describe Image - Understand the Game</title>
<description>To many PTE test takers, describe image question type appears difficult. The reason for this is because they are confused about how to prepare in 25 seconds; what aspects of the image to describe in...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=7</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Repeat Sentence - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>However, to ensure that you get the best scores consistently and with least effort, in this blog we present strategies and tips that will help you achieve...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=6</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Repeat Sentence - Understand the Game</title>
<description>In this blog, we will explain rules of the game that you need to abide by to score well consistently in this item type...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=5</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Read Aloud - How to get the scores you need in one attempt</title>
<description>In this blog, we will present strategies and tips to help you score full points, consistently and efficiently and approach this question type with confidence...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=4</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Read Aloud - Understand the Game</title>
<description>No matter the level of your English Skills; If you understand the machine scoring system;  if you know the English skills that you are lagging in; and if you are smart enough; you can develop ...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=3</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>How to go through our content for one attempt PTE success</title>
<description>Our PTE mock tests and content are designed to help PTE test takers achieve their target scores with ease and in one attempt...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=2</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>Improve English speaking and pronouciation skills while having fun</title>
<description>We have observed this above technique alone has worked wonders amongst our motivated and hardworking students. We have seen students dramatically improve...</description>
<link>https://www.pte-preparation.com/pte-blog-reader.html.php?blogid=1</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:42:16 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>

